# Alex Kenny **Full-stack Developer**

Location / Dun Laoghaire, Dublin, Ireland **Phone** / + 353 85 712 6444 Email / alexkenny1@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

Graduate full-stack developer trained specifically in current front-end and back-end technologies.

Experienced digital marketer and project manager. Previous experience includes medium and large scale web development projects and working knowledge of UX and UI best practice.

Strong interpersonal and communications skills demonstrated throughout a 10+ year career in client relationship management and project management.

# **Skills**

### **Technical Skills**

Wireframe / Balsamiq

Languages / HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python

Frameworks / Flask | Django

Databases / MySQL (PostgresQL) | NoSQL (MongoDB)

Cloud Platforms / Heroku | AWS

Portfolio / al3xk3nny.github.io/portfolio/

#### Soft Skills

- ★ Creative and innovative thinker
- ★ Analytical thinking and decision making
- ★ Teamwork
- **★** Planning and organising

# **Education**

## Code Institute / Diploma in Software Development

2018 - 2018, DUBLIN First Class Honors

#### Griffith College Dublin / Master of Science in Applied Digital Media

2012 - 2014, DUBLIN First Class Honors

#### **Dublin Business School** / Diploma in Project Management

2009 - 2009, DUBLIN Distinction

# Fitzwilliam Institute / Diploma in Advertising

2004 - 2005, DUBLIN

Credit

#### University College Dublin / Bachelor of Arts

2000 - 2003, DUBLIN

Second Class Honors, Grade Two

# Experience

#### **DDFH&B** / Account Director

FEBRUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2018, DUBLIN

Advertising and marketing

Managed a team to deliver successful campaigns on behalf of top performing companies in the insurance, automotive and merchant service industries.

- ★ Played a key role in convincing the Liberty Insurance client to pursue a strategy to prepare young drivers for the *Real Road*. This ultimately became the proposition for 2018's successful *Ready for the Real World* campaign.
- ★ Worked with the AIB Merchant Service and AIB brand marketing teams to coordinate and up-sell the merchant service offering more than doubling their market presence and position within 6 months.
- ★ Took responsibility for GDPR compliance and roll-out across the agency. My approach was ultimately used as a benchmark for other companies within the parent group.

#### WONDR / Digital Producer

AUGUST 2016 - FEBRUARY 2017, DUBLIN

Digital strategy and marketing

Worked collaboratively with WONDR digital architects in the definition and delivery of client's key strategic projects.

- ★ Project managed the successful launch of *Cliff Group* suite of websites.
- ★ Provided strategy and delivery for *Healthy Recipes* and the divisive *Stop Targeting Kids* campaigns for Irish Heart.
- ★ Successful in delivering the Irish Heart website migration project on time and on budget through an agile approach to creative design, media and tech.

# RMG / Senior Digital Account Manager

NOVEMBER 2013 - AUGUST 2016, DUBLIN

Digital and direct marketing

Project managed successful content marketing and digital campaigns on strategy and against agreed KPIs.

- ★ Worked with ATL advertising partners to maintain SuperValu's position as number 1 multiple in the Irish market for 3 successive years.
- ★ Delivered industry recognised web development projects for SuperValu including the 2013/2014 *Real Food* campaign and the 2014/2015 *Good Food Karma* campaign.
- ★ Played a part in the successful pitch for the Laya Healthcare account and managed the digital account thereon, including the first-to-market Laya *Lifetime Community Rating (LCR)* campaign.

# ADFORCE / Senior Agency Account Manager

JANUARY 2010 - JULY 2013, DUBLIN

Mobile advertising and marketing

Worked with sales leadership team to successfully launch Ireland's first mobile ad network whilst enabling brands in the rapidly emerging mobile internet economy.

- ★ Delivered publishing production process definition and improvement for the implementation of mobile rich media technologies.
- ★ Took responsibility to provide lectures in mobile advertising and marketing to brands and skill bodies as part of an up-sell initiative.

Interests

I am a member of a hockey club and enjoy getting involved in the organisational aspects of running a social club. I also enjoy personal technology.